even in the land of super stardom
there's always some new Hollywood Hill
to climb and these days it's not enough
to just be a mega star everyone also
wants to be an entrepreneur
over the years I've seen plenty of
famous faces attach their names to new
business projects launch their own funds
or startups and with the power of social
media celebrities can cut out
traditional marketing and Empire build
in a whole new way
the problem is the very same platforms
that can give any celeb that boost can
also be their downfall
[Music]
having something I never thought I would
do as a business journalist heading to
meet my next guest on a soundstage in a
very special bathroom
Haley Bieber wife of one of the most
famous pop stars in the world and
daughter of the famous Baldwin family is
using a celeb to entrepreneur Playbook
Step 1 launch Beauty brand
Step 2 go direct to your audience on
YouTube
I'm here to find out how she's putting
this content to Commerce strategy to
work
[Music]
we're gonna meet Haley
her hair is so thick she only needs a
few duh hello hello
how's it going how are you good come sit
what are the must-haves in the uh who's
in my bathroom Glam routine I'm always
so big on the skin prep yeah so it has
to be
really good like
hydrating dewy moisturizing skin prep
I'm pretty fast with Glam though like I
just don't like sitting I'm so antsy
like I didn't like sitting in school
either like I just I don't like taking
too long so what's your prep routine
like one interviewer to another I like
for it to flow very naturally it's kind
of like going on a date in what way like
you just ask the person about them and
get to know them the best interviewers
too I feel like are good listeners
totally you're going direct to your
audience with this and you know the
internet's not always a nice place it's
been kind of hard on you sometimes hard
on your marriage it's a more comfortable
experience for me that way I think it's
really hard with the internet as it is
about you know there's there's
narratives that exist for anybody who's
in the public eye and there's narratives
that exist for me that really hurt my
feelings and make me really upset but I
think that I have had a lot more comfort
in being able to create my own content
that I have control over that feels good
for me how are you evolving how you use
social media whether it's YouTube or
Tick Tock or Instagram I've found for
YouTube to be a really embracing
positive place
I have a love-hate relationship with
Tick Tock because I found for it to be a
very nasty negative place when they're
talking about you you have a face and a
voice to the things that are being said
so it feels a lot more of like a
personal
attack on you when you see someone
vocalizing it we've seen so much of you
behind the scenes and like how have you
gotten comfortable
with letting people see you so
vulnerable I do think it has helped
people to see more sides of me and I
think when they get to see me in these
different settings they can at least
just digest and be like oh okay like
that seems like that's how she is and
this is what she does and that's her job
and I would just rather
let people in in a way that's
comfortable for me than always having
assumptions be made about who they think
I am
[Music]
please keep your movements to a minimum
I feel like you you love the 90s Working
Girl look I do I really do I love the
Blazer I love anything very Princess
Diana inspired is there something about
the business
look that appeals to you
I like when you see in a lot of business
style things that you've structured
shoulder a great power suit I've always
kind of gravitated towards stuff like
that so I hear it was entirely your idea
to not just shoot in the bathroom but
eat in the bathroom the concept really
did come from like when you're having a
night out and you're like in the
bathroom with your drink and like fixing
your makeup and you're like chatting
with your girls like oh my God like my
ex is here I always tell people that
like you can go to the Met Gala like the
most crazy part of it is like happening
in the bathroom
import take one
action on daily what's up everyone it's
Haley and welcome to who's in my
bathroom
and I wanted us to be able to have like
real conversations be able to talk about
our passions and our businesses and
things that we love and get silly and
drink tequila and like get a little
tipsy
oh thank you for having me welcome to my
bathroom oh my God it's just like mine
all while doing that on the other side
of things we we were weaving in
conversations early early on about skin
care about beauty about you know we were
like using Road on camera before people
even knew Road this road let's pause one
sec let me get let's cut for a moment
oh yeah
you are the founding partner of road as
well what came first the idea for the
bathroom show or the skincare line one
didn't lead to the other I think uh my
Outlook as an entrepreneur is the worlds
of content and commerce are blending
truly they are married pairing with a
production company and a production
company that's going to let you lead and
let you control the IP whether it's
merch whether it's you know
skin care whatever it is is really
exciting okay well welcome to show thank
you for being here
we're gonna make our grilled cheeses and
we're gonna have a chat okay let's do it
I built obb when I was 26 years old and
she was then like 22 finishing up a Bare
Minerals contract and she was like who
can I turn to that will build with me
and definitely an unconventional Choice
was somebody who started a media company
and you're like at some points are we in
over our head you know maybe I should
have went with a more traditional like
founding partner or maybe I should do I
know what I'm doing and of course that
fear that fear Creeps in you've become
the go-to director producer for
celebrity shows like Kevin Hart Jack
Justin and Haley scaling content that
has racked up billions of views is there
a Changing of the Guard in terms of how
people are reaching their audiences
these days I think
at the level of Fame that a Justin or
Haley or some of these stars have it's
sometimes really
nerve-wracking to go and do content that
you can't control because everything
could get manipulated it's like doing an
interview could we go and create a safe
space where she can go and engage with a
community and most importantly
a Skin Care Community that's what she
really wanted to talk about so you're
working directly with Brands and kind of
cutting out the admin is that a threat
uh yeah to them yeah the audience is
getting so damn smart do not take the
audience for granted uh the idea of a
commercial or forcing a product or
demanding they buy something I think is
a bit archaic I think the old Ad Agency
model is uh dying a little bit
technology is truly allowing
creators to connect directly to Their
audience I frequently look to some of
our big talent and I think oh my Lord
you know if you added up like five six
of them it's like an eighth of the
planet in followers so the question was
used to be great idea packaged how are
we Distributing it the answer is with
them a quick look on Haley's social
accounts and you'll see nods to her
skincare line Road
Haley launched the company in 2022
catching the tail end of a wave of
celebrity brands that have saturated the
beauty Market which raised 1.2 billion
dollars in Venture Capital funding at
its peak
for these Founders Fame is a
double-edged sword it's easier to launch
a brand when you already have so many
eyes on you but what happens when gossip
and drama come for you and your company
there's a lot of folks who think
celebrities don't get into the details
of their brands like what are you doing
here on a day-to-day basis everything
that you could imagine that has to do
with the creative direction of the
entire brand is like that's my job here
and also the formulation is my also the
other thing that I'm the most involved
in so testing the products talking about
what I want to be the next product
figuring out our timeline in the
pipeline and for me the biggest and most
important thing about the brand and the
two biggest things actually are the
aesthetic and what it makes you feel and
then the actual product itself that
you're using I wanted it to be so so so
effective so are you and Justin like
digging into spreadsheets late at night
um him not so much but maybe me a little
bit more he um yeah he's definitely also
I run things by him all the time and he
gives his input and I I appreciate that
for sure before you started a company
what was your impression of Silicon
Valley and what it takes to be a founder
um honestly I didn't really know I don't
really feel like you know what it takes
and what it's like and how it is until
you're actually in the process so I kind
of just always went into it asking a
million and one questions but I feel
like I'm I'm a fast learner and I really
love to absorb information so that was
kind of my biggest thing from the
beginning Elon Musk has said starting a
company is like staring into the abyss
and eating glass
how did it feel for you
um I think anything that you take a leap
of faith with is scary and I think that
you never really know how it's going to
be received until it's out there in the
world and that's a huge risk to take
yeah so no eating glass moments I mean
starting I mean that's like a very like
broad thing you know eating I mean it's
definitely yeah I get there's there's
pains to it there's a lot of growing
pains there's a lot of learning pains
what kind of market research did you do
like did you try everything from
Walgreens to Chanel and where did you
see something missing I remember always
loving going in my mom's bathroom and
trying all her stuff and her creams and
her makeup my grandma she always loved
like creams and skincare she had this
crazy obsession with it my whole life
that always kind of stuck with me and
when the pandemic hit I was like all
right this is the time that I Really
Wanna
nail down what it is I want to do and I
started with exactly what you're talking
about which was trying everything and I
would literally get deliveries of like
hordes of skin care and beauty stuff and
I was just trying everything what works
what doesn't what's popular what's not
and that kind of really helped me hone
down which was already My Philosophy
that like less is more
I found that the more simple that I kept
it
the easier it was to maintain that
routine and the better it was for my
skin who are your beauty business role
models
I think there's a a lot of people that
have gone and done this before me I
think I have a lot of people in my life
and friends of mine that have even
developed their own Brands and
businesses and I'm just like so
impressed by and I think what's nice
about that is there's people to be able
to run things by and have those
conversations with and to be honest I
admire any woman who takes the leap of
faith to launch their own business
initially there was a super long waiting
list yeah was scarcity part of the plan
or part of the strategy people want what
they can't have or no I I almost wish
that it it was because then maybe that
would be a better explanation for why
but it was honestly we did as much
demand planning as we could for what we
were projecting was going to be
the feedback and the popularity but it
just completely far exceeded everyone's
planning and expectations so let's talk
about the growth plan because you are
expanding globally what's the ambition
there where do you want to be
what about new products with Canada that
was what we felt like was the next best
territory to enter into not only because
it is basically the neighbor to the US
but also because my husband's Canadian
so I really felt like Canada needed to
go next and then our plan is to then go
into the UK and we're kind of just
taking it one place at a time obviously
I want it to be everywhere possible I
know you're funding the most of this
with your own money yeah are you
planning to take on new investment or
raise new funding I think if the time
comes where that makes sense and it's
necessary then I will and I would but
for right now it has not been
the case and it hasn't been needed so
we're just trying to take it slow I mean
my goal is to retain as much of the
company as I possibly can as we expand
and as we grow how are you thinking
about an exit strategy like long term do
you want to go public do you want to
sell a big stake like Kylie Jenner I
mean of course like I have my goals for
the brand I have goals that we want to
reach I think that it's important to
have those goals but I'm just like I
just think it's not even really like at
the Forefront of my mind it's kind of
like looming in the background of like
yes eventually I think that's probably
the goal but I just don't even know what
that looks like yet there are a lot of
celebrity Beauty Brands out there some
people think it's almost a cliche yeah
what's going to make yours stand out one
of my biggest things that I noticed with
being a consumer of skincare and Beauty
was like if I went on a website and it
felt like I don't even know what to
choose at this point our approach
is just always going to be that one of
everything good yeah just these curated
edited Essentials and that's why our
drops are always
very much one at a time there have been
a number of celebrity Beauty Brands that
haven't worked out yeah and I wonder if
you you know just being connected to a
famous face isn't enough and that's like
this is from the point of view of
consumers yeah do you worry at all that
you miss the wave
like the wave of the wave of celebrity
Beauty Brands when the economy was going
well and people felt like they had a lot
of disposable income to try new things I
don't feel like that's the case I do
feel like people had a fatigue of
celebrity Beauty Brands that is a tongue
twister
um I do feel like there was a fatigue I
felt like when I announced the brand of
course there was people that were like
oh here we go here's another one and I'm
like I get that I understand I'm also
coming from the point of view where I'm
like
trust me I know but this is my Approach
and it is different to other people and
my goal from the beginning was that this
brand if you took me out of it would
stand on its own regardless of me
internet's always talking there's
people think you might be expanding into
clothes is that for real you trademarked
moves I did trademark what's happening
um I did trademark that for clothes
because I just kind of I like the idea
that this this word mood board like I'm
such a big person that likes to mood
board things
um that's kind of how I
you know I mood board my hair and makeup
inspiration and I mood board inspiration
for the road campaign shoots I mood
board inspiration for my fashion it may
never come to life it may be for
something else who knows but I just kind
of wanted to I'd had that name in my
mind for a long time so we'll stay tuned
maybe stay tuned perhaps mood board will
come to see the light of day okay your
fashion and makeup tips can either spark
like the next big Beauty Trend or
you get some serious backlash and I'm
curious if you're ever surprised how the
world reacts it comes with the territory
I think that it obviously makes me
sad because I feel very misunderstood
and I feel like there's nothing you can
do to try to get people to understand
you and know you but I think that the
the bad side and the negative side of
the internet doesn't outweigh the good
side and the positive side how does it
feel to be someone that so many people
have opinions about
I think it can be hard sometimes but I
also think that you can't expect to
exist in this place and not have that
um so I think sometimes it's just a
harsh
reality check for me I also think it
boils down to
you know having to
learn how to navigate it and be able to
shut all that stuff out and for me it's
like the internet is not real life to me
like my real life with the people that I
love is my real life and sometimes it's
hard to just stay there and stay focused
on that when things
online can feel loud and disruptive I
don't think there's anything in the
world that can prepare someone to
step into such a broad
um
amount of scrutiny and being talked
about and it kind of just like really
puts you under a crazy magnifying glass
and I had just never experienced that
before so I feel like I've seen you
leaning into it a little more or almost
accepting it a little more like the
nepotism thing you stepped out in a nepo
baby t-shirt explain that
um the nepo baby t-shirt was just meant
to be my little comment on the the whole
discourse that had been going around and
you know my point to having worn the
T-shirt was not to poke fun at it or
kind of be like yeah I'm a nepo baby and
haha type of a thing was more so to be
like this is what everyone is saying and
I want you to know that this is my way
of responding to it in my way of
acknowledging it in a way that is so
overly literal that it's like I'm just
gonna call myself a nepo baby because I
am one and I embrace that I am but I
thought what was funny about that is
like to me the way the internet is is
like nothing's ever enough so it's like
I do that and it's like half of people
find it funny and they get the humor
behind it and they got it and then half
the people are like we are not even
really a nepo baby like that much I'm
like so you're gonna sit there and call
me a nipple baby all day long but then I
acknowledge it and then I'm not enough
of a nepo baby so it's like there is
never any like winning with the internet
and that's what I've always time and
time again realize I'm probably too old
to understand why this is an issue but
here we go there's some ongoing drama
between you another celebrity and
eyebrows and
you reach out to her saying you've been
getting death threats and she told her
fans to stop I don't think that this is
about me Haley Bieber and Selena Gomez
this is not about this
pitting between two women and division
between two women it's about
the
vile disgusting hatred that can come
from
completely made up and twisted and
perpetuated narratives that can be
really dangerous and I think that
it's an opportunity to
really stand for bringing people
together and not being okay with the
kind of division that it costs because
I'm not okay with the kind of division
that I cause I don't I don't like this
whole idea of team this person and team
this person I'm just not about that I
want to
be able to bring people together and I
think that that was a really important
moment for people to see that
you can do that and you can bring people
together and it doesn't have to be about
this divisive nature it's such a
frustrating old narrative like two women
being pitted against each other over
because of a guy it's awful I hate it
I've hated it since the beginning and
I think that kind of goes back to a
little bit of just being misunderstood
when it's like
time and time again I don't know why I
keep having to say and we keep having to
say that there is no issue and there is
no problem it's so disappointing that
people still behave this way because of
a like over a man it's yeah it's the
world we live in unfortunately backlash
can be so Swift and Fierce and
Relentless and now you've got this
business right like how do you think
about that and how you know when public
opinion sways what does it mean for the
brand what does it mean for the business
My head goes there because this brand is
so important to me and of course I don't
want
silly made up drama to affect what I'm
focused and working on
um and I think at the end of the day you
kind of just have to
keep it pushing and just keep moving
forward it doesn't mean that the work
falls to the side because of noise and
because things are being said because
there's always going to be noise and
there's always going to be things that
are said and if it's not that it's going
to be something else so it's kind of
about just knowing
just how to navigate it as it comes
because it wasn't the first time and it
won't be the last time what's the
biggest lesson you've learned from
starting a business the biggest lesson
I've learned is that there's going to be
mishaps and mistakes and the problem for
me is that I'm a perfectionist so
when
issues come up or problems arise or
there's hiccups I'm like like how do we
stop it and fix it and it's like it
actually is just part of the learning
process and sometimes the learning is
really hard
especially if you're like a
perfectionist people pleaser people
pleaser I feel like I hear a lot of
women say that a lot do you feel like
that's one of your flaws or just part of
your character I think it's something
that I struggle with yeah for sure I
don't necessarily think it's a flaw the
base of where I think that comes from is
I just care so much I care so deeply
about people I care about my like I'm a
people pleaser with my friends with like
with every aspect of my life with
everything that you're doing and there's
so much more than Road the YouTube shows
the you know the fashion and makeup tips
are we seeing you try to separate the
Haley from the Bieber and the fall twin
at all it's hard to say that you can
separate it because it's like
this is my life that is the family I
come from and that is my husband there
is no denying that and I don't want to
try to run away from that I'd like to
just Embrace that so I think there's a
space that within all of that for people
to understand take any last name out of
it like who exactly is Haley and I think
my journey with the YouTube channel and
kind of the Vlog Style videos I put out
is really just for people to be able to
connect to who Haley is without
the last names without the headlines
without the gossip without all that
other stuff and just
form their own connection to me
personally as much as that's possible
through right social media so 10 years
from now what do you want people to be
talking about I know what I don't want
them to be talking about anymore I
always want road to be a reflection of
my life and where I'm at and what's
going on with me in that time so I feel
like if I see that being motherhood in a
different space then I feel like the
brand in some ways will definitely
reflect that as well well you are
multi-platform in a multimedia world
yeah and it continues and it's been
really fun there's nothing better than
being able to kind of really have
ownership over your own platform and it
be this this this machine that's kind of
funneling all things in one space
[Music]
thank you